Natalie Graser

22050 Eastside Drive Apt 606, Ashburn, VA 20147 | NRGraser@outlook.com | 571.762.7701

Skills, Course Work, and Research Areas:

Understanding of the fundamental concepts of software development along with applied computer programming and problem-solving skills. Experience with Raptor, Python, Rust, Java, C, C#, C++, Microsoft .NET, SQL, and Linux. Can configure comprehensive security policies in Windows Server, Windows Vista, 7, 8, and 10, and Linux Ubuntu platforms. Capable of setting up and utilizing virtual machines. Competent in Google Docs and MS Office platforms.

Education:

- Master of Science in Computer Science (Projected completion May 2024)
 - o Old Dominion University, Norfolk, VA
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (December 2022)
 - o Old Dominion University, Norfolk, VA
 - o Magna Cum Laude

Experience:

- **Support Engineer** (April 2022 Current)
 - o Amazon Web Services, Herndon, VA
 - o Perform user acceptance testing prior to launching new software features to customers.
 - Develop comprehensive test cases for regression testing in order to move towards testing automation.
- **Data Technician** (April 2020 April 2022)
 - o Amazon Web Services, Ashburn, VA
 - Work on a variety of break/fix issues regarding day-to-day operations within AWS data centers, through a ticketing system that requires replacing hardware, troubleshooting Linux servers, and troubleshooting network connectivity issues.
- **DevOps Engineer** (August 2019 April 2020)
 - o Avenity, Inc., Fairfax VA
 - Fullstack software development of several tax processing applications using Microsoft .Net (C#, WinForms, IIS/ASP/MVC) and relation database systems (Oracle and SQL Server) for multiple locality governments in Virginia reaching approximately 1 million people
- United States Air Force Academy (June 2017 February 2019)
 - o USAFA, CO
- Virginia Space Grant Consortium (Summer 2016)
 - o NASA, Langley Research Center
 - High school academy for an elite cadre of rising seniors that spend their summer at NASA's Langley Research Center working with NASA on future mission planning and developing teamwork and mission-oriented problem-solving skills.
- **Cyber Patriot** (2014-2017)
 - National Youth Cyber Education Program
 - O Cyber defense competition in which competitors set security policies in Windows Server, 7, 8, 10 or Linux Ubuntu platforms, as well as completing Cisco networking challenges
 - O Developed skills in PowerShell, batch files, desktop setup, and security policies
 - State Champions in All Service Platinum Division (2016), Team Captain (2017)

Community Service and Volunteer Activities:

• 20 hours/ month as an officer and Nationally Registered EMT at the Centreville Volunteer Fire Department